Start to check the command!
Command valid! Start to run!
We have read:
whoever it was
he
or she
would always say:

That is a hat.

Then I would never talk to that person about boa constrictors
or primeval forests
or stars. I would bring myself down to his level. I would talk to him about bridge
and golf
and politics
and neckties. And the grown-up would be greatly pleased to have met such a sensible man.






[ Chapter 2 ]

- the narrator crashes in the desert and makes the acquaintance of the little prince



So I lived my life alone
without anyone that I could really talk to
until I had an accident with my plane in the Desert of Sahara
six years ago. Something was broken in my engine. And as I had with me neither a mechanic nor any passengers
I set myself to attempt the difficult repairs all alone. It was a question of life or death for me: I had scarcely enough drinking water to last a week.

The first night
then
I went to sleep on the sand
a thousand miles from any human habitation. I was more isolated than a shipwrecked sailor on a raft in the middle of the ocean. Thus you can imagine my amazement
at sunrise
when I was awakened by an odd little voice. It said:

If you please-- draw me a sheep!

What!

Draw me a sheep!

I jumped to my feet
completely thunderstruck. I blinked my eyes hard. I looked carefully all around me. And I saw a most extraordinary small person
who stood there examining me with great seriousness. Here you may see the best potrait that
later
I was able to make of him. But my drawing is certainly very much less charming than its model.



That
however
is not my fault. The grown-ups discouraged me in my painter's career when I was six years old
and I never learned to draw anything
except boas from the outside and boas from the inside.

Now I stared at this sudden apparition with my eyes fairly starting out of my head in astonishment. Remember
I had crashed in the desert a thousand miles from any inhabited region. And yet my little man seemed neither to be straying uncertainly among the sands
nor to be fainting from fatigue or hunger or thirst or fear. Nothing about him gave any suggestion of a child lost in the middle of the desert
a thousand miles from any human habitation. When at last I was able to speak
I said to him:

But-- what are you doing here?

And in answer he repeated
very slowly
as if he were speaking of a matter of great consequence: "If you please-- draw me a sheep..."

When a mystery is too overpowering
one dare not disobey. Absurd as it might seem to me
a thousand miles from any human habitation and in danger of death
I took out of my pocket a sheet of paper and my fountain-pen. But then I remembered how my studies had been concentrated on geography
history
arithmetic
and grammar
and I told the little chap (a little crossly
too) that I did not know how to draw. He answered me:

That doesn't matter. Draw me a sheep...

But I had never drawn a sheep. So I drew for him one of the two pictures I had drawn so often. It was that of the boa constrictor from the outside. And I was astounded to hear the little fellow greet it with


No
no
no! I do not want an elephant inside a boa constrictor. A boa constrictor is a very dangerous creature
and an elephant is very cumbersome. Where I live
everything is very small. What I need is a sheep. Draw me a sheep.

So then I made a drawing.



He looked at it carefully
then he said:

No. This sheep is already very sickly. Make me another.

So I made another drawing.



My friend smiled gently and indulgenty.

You see yourself

he said
that this is not a sheep. This is a ram. It has horns.

So then I did my drawing over once more.



But it was rejected too
just like the others.

This one is too old. I want a sheep that will live a long time.

By this time my patience was exhausted
because I was in a hurry to start taking my engine apart. So I tossed off this drawing.



And I threw out an explanation with it.

This is only his box. The sheep you asked for is inside.

I was very surprised to see a light break over the face of my young judge:

That is exactly the way I wanted it! Do you think that this sheep will have to have a great deal of grass?

Why?

Because where I live everything is very small...

There will surely be enough grass for him

I said. "It is a very small sheep that I have given you."

He bent his head over the drawing:

Not so small that-- Look! He has gone to sleep...

And that is how I made the acquaintance of the little prince.






[ Chapter 3 ]

- the narrator learns more about from where the little prince came



It took me a long time to learn where he came from. The little prince
who asked me so many questions
never seemed to hear the ones I asked him. It was from words dropped by chance that
little by little
everything was revealed to me.

The first time he saw my airplane
for instance (I shall not draw my airplane; that would be much too complicated for me)
he asked me:

What is that object?

That is not an object. It flies. It is an airplane. It is my airplane.

And I was proud to have him learn that I could fly.

He cried out
then:

What! You dropped down from the sky?

Yes

I answered
modestly.

Oh! That is funny!

And the little prince broke into a lovely peal of laughter
which irritated me very much. I like my misfortunes to be taken seriously.

Then he added:

So you
too
come from the sky! Which is your planet?

At that moment I caught a gleam of light in the impenetrable mystery of his presence; and I demanded
abruptly:

Do you come from another planet?

But he did not reply. He tossed his head gently
without taking his eyes from my plane:

It is true that on that you can't have come from very far away...

And he sank into a reverie
which lasted a long time. Then
taking my sheep out of his pocket
he buried himself in the contemplation of his treasure.

You can imagine how my curiosity was aroused by this half-confidence about the "other planets." I made a great effort
therefore
to find out more on this subject.

My little man
where do you come from? What is this 'where I live
' of which you speak? Where do you want to take your sheep?

After a reflective silence he answered:

The thing that is so good about the box you have given me is that at night he can use it as his house.

That is so. And if you are good I will give you a string
too
so that you can tie him during the day
and a post to tie him to.

But the little prince seemed shocked by this offer:

Tie him! What a queer idea!

But if you don't tie him

I said
he will wander off somewhere
and get lost.

My friend broke into another peal of laughter:

But where do you think he would go?

Anywhere. Straight ahead of him.

Then the little prince said
earnestly:

That doesn't matter. Where I live
everything is so small!

And
with perhaps a hint of sadness
he added:

Straight ahead of him
nobody can go very far...





[ Chapter 4 ]

- the narrator speculates as to which asteroid from which the little prince came






I had thus learned a second fact of great importance: this was that the planet the little prince came from was scarcely any larger than a house!

But that did not really surprise me much. I knew very well that in addition to the great planets-- such as the Earth
Jupiter
Mars
Venus-- to which we have given names
there are also hundreds of others
some of which are so small that one has a hard time seeing them through the telescope. When an astronomer discovers one of these he does not give it a name
but only a number. He might call it
for example
Asteroid 325.




I have serious reason to believe that the planet from which the little prince came is the asteroid known as B-612.

This asteroid has only once been seen through the telescope. That was by a Turkish astronomer
in 1909.
